A Guide to the Papers of Elsie Fowke Jackson, 1652-1980
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Elsie Fowke Jackson 1652-1980
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6589-l
This collection consists of ca. 500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This accession was given to the Library by Elsie Fowke Jackson of Alexandria, Virginia, on October 12, 1982.
Scope and Content Information
This accession consists of ca. 500 items, 1652-1980, primarily concerning the Fowke and Reed families. The types of material include correspondence, legal documents, genealogical notes and charts, photographs, newspaper clippings, a diary, business papers, and memorabilia. Some of the items are electrostatic copies of the originals. Many of the items pertain to the life and activities of Elsie Fowke Jackson, including her extensive genealogical notes regarding the following families: Chandler, Daniel, Dorsey, Fowke, Harrison, Jenkins, Mason, Reed, Rolph, and Washington. Also included are four seventeenth century legal documents including a land grant, 1665 from William Berkeley, governor of Virginia, to Gerard Fowke.
Contents List
- Elsie Jackson's autograph and typed transcriptions of letter from John Reed to Joseph [Reed], w/additional notes [1861 May 2]
- Miscellaneous: military discharge of William J. Fowke; [Y] W. Fallin to C. R. Railey; Lawrence Richey, Secretary to U. S. President, to O. A. C. Oehmler 1864, 1970, 1932
- Reed Family correspondence 1869-1929
- Fowkes corespondence 1888-1929, n.d.
- Letters to Elsie Fowkes Jackson w/other material re E. F. Jackson 1936-1980, n.d.
- Land grant of Richard Benonelt to George Foster 1 Sept 1652
- Land grant of Garrard [sic] Fowke to Richard Hope 1664 July 7
- Grant of land to Gerrard Fowke by Sir William Berkeley 1665 Oct 17
- Deed of land sale of James Ashton to Charles Ansell 1679 June 11
- Deed of land sale of Thomas M. Washington and Catharine Washington to John Reed 1819 June 24
- Marriage agreement between Samuel Fowke and Ellen Jenkins (copy) 1844 Jan 23
- Deed of land sale of John and Harriet Jenkins to John Reed 1850 Aug 31
- Receipts and business papers of Capt. R. T. Fowke and others 1860, 1869-1913
- Miscellaneous Reed legal and military papers, w/R. B. Reed's survey and map (electronic copy) [1860], 1865, 1867, [1907]
- Checks, receipts, and business papers of Robert B. Reed 1874-1916
- Deeds of Robert B. Reed 1881-1893, 1916
- Miscellaneous fragments n.d.
- Chandler: genealogical information n.d.
- Daniel, Dorsey, Mason, and Rolph Families: genealogical information 1950, 1974, n.d.
- Fowke: Elsie Jackson's typed manuscripts, genealogical charts, extensive notes, and photocopied material n.d.
- Harrison: genealogcial notes and information n.d.
- Jenkins: genealogical notes and photocopied material n.d.
- Reed: genealogical notes and information n.d.
- Washington: genealogical notes and information n.d.
- Miscellaneous genealogical notes of Elsie Jackson n.d.
- Memorabilia ca. 1800-ca. 1975, n.d.
- Sheet of music from Susan Fowke's harpsichord music lesson book w/electrostatic copy 1870 Jan 20
- "In Memoriam," poem by J. W. Reed re death of his wife; autograph verse of "Miss Sutton" [to J. B. Bryant?]; autograph verse of unknown authors 1873, 1881, n.d.
- Printed material 1880-1970, n.d.
- Photographs re Fowke family 1890, 1912, n.d.
- Newspaper clippings 1905-1978, n.d.
- Photographs of Elsie F. Jackson 1923-ca. 1968
- Miscellaneous photographs and prints 1935, 1962-1963
- Photographs re "Woodlawn" (Virginia), Bethel School of Nursing (Shanghai, China), and Venezuela 1944, 1948, n.d.
- Typed manuscripts of Elbert B. Rose re Lincoln and American flag 1959, n.d.
- Misecllaneous issues of The Potomac Sentinel1970-1972
- Photographs re Reed family n.d.
- Miscellaneous photocopied material w/annotation n.d.
- Application for membership in National Society Colonial Dames and genealogical notes of Elsie Jackson pulled from bound vol. 1 n.d.
- Diary of [?] 1967 May-Dec
- Family Tree by William H. Whitmore, w/genealogical charts compiled by Elsie F. Jackson ca. 1963
- Pages from deed book re Fowke Family (electrostatic copies) [1844-45]
- Mason Family genealogcial chart (printed copy) 1907
- Pencil drawings of Elsie Fowke 1926
- Reed-Fowke (1614-1952) genealogical chart, compiled by Elsie F. Jackson 1965
- Genealogical chart of the Fitzhugh-Grymes Family 1971
- Map of George Washington's route to New York for Inauguration (transparency, w/copy) n.d.